Guide to the Tile Layers and Helpers Union Local 20 Records, 1907-1945 AIS.1989.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Tile Layers and Helpers Union Local 20 Records
1907-1945
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Tile Layers and Helpers Union. Local 26 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
Tile Layers and Helpers Union. Local 20 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1989.04
1.7 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Tile Layers and Helpers were an American Federation of Labor union with Local 20 succeeding Local 26 in Pittsburgh, Pa. This collection includes ledgers from these locals, as well as photographs of business agent and Pittsburgh labor leader Michael J. Dorsey.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Michael J. Dorsey in January 1989.
History
The Tile Layers and Helpers were an American Federation of Labor union. The precise name, number and international union-affiliation of the local varied over time. Tile Layers Local 20 appears to have succeeded Local 26 (ca. 1919) and to have been affiliated at various times in its history with: the Ceramic, Mosaic, and Encuastic Tile Layers and Helpers International Union; the Marble, Slate Stone Polishers, Rubbers, and Sawyers, Marble and Tile Helpers International Union; and the Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers International Union of America.
Michael J. Dorsey served in several elected positions within Local 20, including business agent. He also headed the AFL Central Labor Union from 1942 to 1950. He passed away in 1956.
Previous Citation
Tile Layers and Helpers Local 20 Records, 1907-1945, AIS.1989.04, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains dues ledgers and minute books from Local 26 and 20. Also present if a financial day book. These records contain member names and information such as military service, international union membership number, and beneficiary. Photographs of Local 20 and Michael Dorsey, business agent of the local, are also included.
Related Material
Pittsburgh Central Labor Union Records, 1929-1959, AIS.1996.04, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh
Pittsburgh (Pa.); Tile layers -- Labor unions –- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; Ceramic, Mosaic, and Encuastic Tile Layers and Helpers International Union; Tile Layers and Helpers Union. Local 26 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Dorsey, Michael J.; Tile Layers and Helpers Union. Local 20 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers International Union of America; Marble, Slate Stone Polishers, Rubbers, and Sawyers, Marble and Tile Helpers International Union
- Tile Layers and Helpers Locals 26 and 20, I
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains the records of Tile Layers and Helpers Local 26 and its successor, Local 20. Included are meeting minutes, dues ledgers, and correspondence.
  - Minute Book, June 22, 1916-September 7, 1938 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Local 26 Dues Ledger, 1907-1909 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Local 26 Dues Ledger, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Volume 4)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1922 (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Volume 8)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Volume 9)
  - Local 20 Dues Ledger, 1930-1935 (Box 1, Volume 10)
  - Local 20 Day Book, August 1927-September 1945 (Box 1, Volume 11)
  - Correspondence, 1924-1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership Application Forms, 1920s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Blank Stationary, 1910s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dues Summary Sheets, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Financial Notes, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Attendants of the Tile Layers Annual Picnic, August 14, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - List of Helpers and Employers, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Michael J.Dorsey Papers, II.
  This collection contains photographs of Michael J. Dorsey, a Pittsburgh labor leader, and the American Federation of Labor's Central Labor Union. Also included are newsclippings of Dorsey's obituaries and mourners' registers which contain the signatures of those who attended his funeral.
  - Mourners' Register for Michael J. Dorsey Funeral, 1956 (Box 2, Volume 1-2)
  - Newsclippings regarding Michael J. Dorsey, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Doresey and the Central Labor Union (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Michael J. Dorsey with Mayor David L. Lawrence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Central Labor Union Photograph (duplicate print) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photograph of Dorsey's Son (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Michael J. Dorsey, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Photograph of Michael J. Dorsey, 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 11)
  - Photograph of the Ban Ban Brotherhood of America, Patrick Pearse Circle, 2.